Howie Hao Wang

About Me

A web designer and developer with a background in architecture.

My professional experience started at We-Work. I was fascinated by how a data-driven approach is implemented in the design. Later at SOM, I worked on <u>an interior project</u> <u>involving VR</u>.

My diverse background prepares me with both design and development skills: A keen eye for design; professional experience using design tools; solving real-world problems through design thinking, research and analytical skills.

- *1. watch a self-introduction video;
- *2. watch a portfolio presentation.

Education

University of Virginia

Aug. 2015 - Dec. 2017 | Charlottesville, VA

- · Master of Architecture, Scholarship
- · GPA: 3.61, GRE: 319 *Full score in Math.

University of Mining and Technology Sep. 2010 - Jul. 2015 | Xuzhou, China

- · Bachelor of Architecture, Full Scholarship
- · GPA: 3.89, Rank: 2/86

Software Engineering Student

Mar. 2021 - Current | at Udemy & freeCodeCamp.org

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, Redux, Node-JS, Express, Python, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Flask, Jest

- Self-curated software engineering course totaling over 600 hours in length
- Built numerous projects from scratch using web development technologies
- Actively worked in online communities to learn workflow and achieve goals.
- · Worked with Data Structure & Algorithm
- Completed courses list and earned certification

Skills

Frontend

React, Redux, JavaScript (ES6), TypeScript, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS

Backend

NodeJS, Express, PostgreSQL, Flask

Tools & Platforms

Git, Netlify, Heroku, Vercel, Wordpress, Firebase, MongoDB

Design

Adobe Creative Suite (Photoshop, InDesign, Illustrator), Figma, Adobe XD

Other

Git, GitHub, Unit testing, Agile, Next, Python, Data Structure & Algorithm, Video Edit, Bilingual in Chinese and English

- howiework.com
- (1) 434-227-8996
- howiewang2020@gmail.com

github.com/HowieWork





Projects

Full Stack Developer at Snap App, Nov. - Dec. 2021

React, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Responsive Design

- Designed and developed Snap App, a photo-sharing platform for people who love architecture. <u>Product Video Demo</u>
- Wrote frontend *React and backend *NodeJS; Set up database *MongoDB for snaps and users. <u>GitHub Source Code</u>
- Fixed bugs in React to improve UX/UI. Tested sites in various browsers and devices to ensure cross-browser compatibility and mobile responsiveness.
- · Inspired by real-life experience as an architectural designer. Read the Full Story

Full Stack Developer at Lunch Break, Jan. - Feb. 2022

NextJS, React, NodeJS, Express, MongoDB, Vercel, Responsive Design

- An MVP blog site cares about work-life balance focusing on design, psychology and community. It derived from my own WeChat Official Account. Users can make comments and interact with authors.
- The first article has reached 826 reads. Over 20,000 words have been published since launching. Read why and how I built Lunch Break.
- Designed, developed and shipped interactive web application using Vercel. <u>GitHub Source</u>
 Code

Product Designer at Museum App *NMAAHC, Oct. 2019 - Jan. 2020

AdobeXD, FlowMapp, Photoshop, Illustrator, Indesign

- · A mobile app design for a museum. The goal is to enhance the visiting experience.
- Personal product project contains the whole process including UX research, UI Design, Prototype, Testing and Design Package.
- Collaborate closely with the community from different backgrounds including student designers, marketing team, and techies.

React Guide | Built with React

React, Redux, Function Component, Custom Hooks, Unit Testing, Jest

 I am currently working on my guide for React including general components, patterns, and interview questions.

<u>Howiework</u> | Built with React; Hosted by <u>GitHub</u> page React, Markdown, Responsive Design, Accessibility

• I completely redesign and rebuild my portfolio website using React. It is a major update from the <u>previous design version</u> for my aspiring dev career.

Experience

Designer / Developer / Consultant

Mar. 2020 — present | Freelance, Washington DC

- Worked with clients from different backgrounds to ensure requirements were met; Help clients rebrand; Build portfolio sites with WordPress/Squarespace.
- · Worked on projects like Snap App, LunchBreak, and NMAAHC mobile app.

Product Designer / Developer

Jul. 2019 — Mar. 2020 | Remote

- Helped the client solidify a brand direction for the MIAO product to span across print, packaging, web and their store-front design.
- · Interfaced with clients daily, providing technological expertise and knowledge.

Architectural Professional at Skidmore, Owings & Merrill LLP (SOM)

Jun. 2018 — Jul. 2019 | Washington DC

- · Worked with a team of four designers on an interior office HQ Project: work on SD, DD, CD.
- · Integrated modern technology, e.g. VR into the presentation.

Designer at WeWork

Feb. 2018 — May 2018 | New York, NY

- Communicate and collaborate with multi-disciplinary teams of engineers, designers, clients, and stakeholders daily.
- · Implemented data-driven design approach and research on space & profit efficiency.